Pretty much all the robots we're interested in for this course,
このコースで関心を持つほとんどすべてのロボットは
share the same basic characteristics.
同じ基本的な特徴を共有します
They contain sensors for perceiving the world around them,
それらには 周囲の世界を認識するセンサー
software for making high level decisions,
高度な決定を行うソフトウェア
and motors and controllers for actuation.
作動用のモーターやコントローラがあります
ROS provides a powerful communications system
ROS には これらの異なるコンポーネントが互いに通信できる
allowing these different components to communicate with one another.
強力な通信システムが用意されています
Here, we'll introduce this communication system by considering a generic robot.
ここで この通信システムを一般的なロボットを検討しながら紹介します
This robot could be a drone,
このロボットは ドローン 移動基地局 または
a mobile base or even a robotic arm.
ロボットアームとすることができます
While these robots may be composed of very different physical components,
これらのロボットは まったく異なる物理コンポーネントで構成できますが
they are all built to perform these same three high level steps of perception,
すべてが認識 意思決定 作動の 3 つの同じ高度なステップを
decision making and actuation.
実行するよう構築されています
On the software side,
ソフトウェア側では ROS がこれら 3 つの
ROS manages these three complex steps by breaking
複雑なステップをノードと呼ばれる多くの小さい
each of them down into many small unit processes called nodes.
ユニットプロセスにそれぞれ細分化して管理します
Typically, each node on the system is responsible for
通常はシステムの各ノードが ロボット全体の機能のうち
one small and relatively specific portion of the robot's overall functionality.
小さく比較的特定の一部分を担当します
For example, there may be nodes for each sensor and actuator in the system,
たとえば システムには各センサーやアクチュエーター向けの
as well as nodes for things like position estimation,
ノードのほか ローカライゼーション 動作実行 モーター制御のようなもの向けの
behavior execution and motor control.
ノードもあるでしょう
At the center of this collection of nodes is
このノードの集まりの中心は ROS マスターで
the ROS Master which acts as a sort of manager of all the nodes.
すべてのノードの管理者のように振る舞います
The ROS Master maintains a registry of all the active nodes on a system.
ROS マスターは システムでアクティブになっているすべてのノードのレジストリを管理します
It then allows each node to discover other nodes in
そして 各ノードがシステム内の他のノードを検出し
the system and establish lines of communication with them.
それらとの通信のラインを確立できるようにします
In addition to allowing nodes to locate one another and communicate,
ノードが互いを見つけて通信できるようにするだけでなく
the ROS Master also hosts what's called the parameter server.
ROS マスターはいわゆるパラメーターサーバーのホストも行います
As its name suggests,
その名が示すように
the parameter server is typically used to store parameters
パラメーターサーバーは通常 実行中のノード間で共有される
and configuration values that are shared amongst the running nodes.
パラメーターや構成値の格納に使用されます
For example, a mobile robot's wheel radius may be used by
たとえばモバイルロボットのホイール半径は あるノードでは
one node to estimate position and by another to calculate speed.
ローカライゼーションのために使用し 別のノードでは速度計算に使用できます
Rather than storing the same information in multiple places,
同じ情報を複数の場所に格納する代わりに
nodes can look up values as needed.
ノードは必要に応じて値を調べることができます
Nodes can also share data with one
ノードは トピックと呼ばれるメッセージを渡すことによって
another by passing messages over what are called topics.
互いにデータを共有することもできます
A topic is simply a named bus which you can think of as
トピックは メッセージが通過するノード間のパイプとして
a pipe between nodes through which messages flow.
考えることができる単なる名前の付いたバスです
In order to send a message on a topic,
トピックでメッセージを送信するには
we say that a node must publish to it.
ノードはトピックにパブリッシュする必要があります
Likewise, to receive a message on a topic,
同様にメッセージをトピックで受信するには
a node must subscribe to it.
ノードがトピックにサブスクライブする必要があります
Here's an example of the topics,
これが さきほど説明したノード用のトピック
publishers and subscribers for the nodes we introduced earlier.
パブリッシャー サブスクライバーの例です
The arrows represent message flow from publishers to subscribers.
矢印はパブリッシャーからサブスクライバーへのメッセージフローを表しています
It's important to note that each node may
各ノードがさまざまなトピックに対して同時にパブリッシュや
simultaneously publish and subscribe to a wide variety of topics.
サブスクライブする場合があることを認識しておくことが大切です
Taken together, this network of nodes connected by topics is
トピックで接続されたこのノードのネットワークをまとめて
called publish subscribe or a pub sub architecture.
パブリッシュサブスクライブまたはパブサブアーキテクチャといいます